trakt.tv 2019-12-23

# Privacy Policy - Trakt.tv

Trakt provides this Privacy Policy to inform you of our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personal information we receive from users of trakt.tv and subdomains ("Sites"). This Privacy Policy applies only to information that you provide to us through these Sites. Our Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time, and we will notify you of any material changes by posting the new Privacy Policy for the Sites at http://trakt.tv/privacy.

Trakt complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States.  Trakt has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles.  If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

##  **1.** Information Collection: The Personally Identifiable Information We Collect

In the course of using Trakt Sites, you may provide us with personally identifiable information. This refers to information about you that can be used to contact or identify you, and information on your use of and activities at our Sites that may be connected with you ("Personal Information"). Personal Information that we collect may include, but is not limited to, your name, email address, and location. Personal Information may also include information you supply to us concerning your preferences and interests expressed in the course of use of our Sites, as well as the content which you have viewed on the Sites. Your use of the Sites to record your preferences, identify content relevant to you, and otherwise personalize your activity in relation to the Sites is intended for your benefit; however, we want to make you aware as described below how we use your Personal Information.

When you visit the Sites, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website. This information may include, but is not limited to, your computer's Internet Protocol address, browser type, the web page you were visiting before you came to our Sites and information you search for on our Sites. Like many websites, we may also use "cookies" to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes. We may use "persistent cookies" to save your username and password for future logins to the Sites; and we use "session ID cookies" to enable certain features of the Sites, to better understand how you interact with the Sites and to monitor aggregate usage and web traffic routing on the Sites. You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Sites or all functionality of our services.

##  **2.** How We Use Personal Information

Personal Information is or may be used for the following purposes: (i) to provide and improve our Sites, services, features and content, (ii) to administer your use of our Sites, (iii) to enable you to enjoy and easily navigate the Sites, (iv) to better understand your needs and interests, (v) to fulfill requests you may make, or (vi) to personalize your experience. We may use your Personal Information to identify which third-party ad content is relevant to you (change your settings here). We may use your contact information to provide or offer (including via e-mail) software updates and product announcements, and to provide you with further information and offers from us or third parties that we believe you may find useful or interesting, including newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information on services and products offered by us or third parties. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive any such communications, please follow the "unsubscribe" instructions provided in any of the communications sent to you, or you may opt-out of receiving communications at any time by updating your "account settings" information. (See "Changing or Deleting Personal Information" below.)

We use information we obtain by technical means (such as the automatic recording performed by our servers or through the use of cookies) for the above purposes and in order to monitor and analyze use of the Sites and our services, for the Sites technical administration, to increase our Sites functionality and user-friendliness, to better tailor it to your needs, to generate and derive useful data and information concerning the interests, characteristics and website use behavior of our users, and to verify that visitors to these Sites meet the criteria required to process their requests.

##  **3.** Information Sharing and Disclosure

 **Trakt Users.** We will display your Personal Information in your profile page and elsewhere on the Sites according to the preferences you set in your account. Any information you choose to provide should reflect how much you want other Trakt users to know about you. We recommend that you guard your anonymity and sensitive information, and we encourage users to think carefully about what information about themselves they disclose in their profile pages. You can review and revise your profile information at any time.

 **Service Providers, Business Partners and Others.** We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our service, to provide the service on our behalf, to perform Sites-related services (including but not limited to data storage, maintenance services, database management, web analytics, payment processing, and improvement of the Sites features) or to assist us in analyzing how our Sites and service are used. These third parties have access to your Personal Information only for purposes of performing these tasks on our behalf, and we endeavor to provide only the portion of the Personal information that is relevant to these tasks.

Trakt will only provide your Personal Information with third parties pursuant to an agreement with the third party that provides it will preserve your Personal Information, and will not share your Personal Information except as instructed by Trakt. Trakt remains responsible for treatment of your Personal Information in the hands of such third party pursuant to this Privacy Policy, unless we can prove that we acted reasonably are not responsible for any harm caused by the third-party, such as the third party’s negligence or misconduct. Trakt will work with third parties with whom it shares your Personal Information to address any concerns or incidents.

 **Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement.** Trakt cooperates with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (including but not limited to subpoenas), to protect the property and rights of Trakt or a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop any activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, illegal, unethical, inappropriate or legally actionable.

 **Business Transfers.** Trakt may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including your Personal Information, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets or in the event of bankruptcy.

 **International Transfers.** Trakt stores Personal Information in the cloud, our servers, and the servers of our service providers. To facilitate our global operations, we may transfer and access such information from around the world, including to servers located in the United States. By providing information to Trakt, you consent to the transfer and storage of Personal Information in these locations.

##  **4.** Requesting Your Personal Information

You may request a copy of your Personal Information by emailing us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#a8dbddd8d8c7dadce8dcdac9c3dc86dcde) with a subject of **Personal Information Request**. Please send the email from the same address attached to your Trakt account and include your Trakt username to verify your identity. We will respond within 30 days with JSON files containing all your information.

##  **5.** Changing or Deleting Your Personal Information

You may review, update, correct or delete the Personal Information provided in your registration or account profile by changing your account settings. You may delete your Trakt account in your account settings by clicking on the **Delete Account** link. Deleting your account removes any Personal Information attached with your account and anonymizes your statistical data.

##  **6.** Security

Trakt is very concerned with safeguarding your information. We employ reasonable measures designed to protect your information from unauthorized access.

##  **7.** Our Policy Toward Children

This Sites is not directed to children under 18. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#10636560607f6264506462717b643e6466). If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will delete such information from our files.

##  **8.** Issue Resolution

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Trakt commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact Trakt at: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#f685838686998482b68284979d82d88280). Trakt has further committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning data transferred from the EU.

The Federal Trade Commission has jurisdiction over Trakt’s compliance with the Privacy Shield. In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint, you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

##  **9.** Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#ff8c8a8f8f908d8bbf8b8d9e948bd18b89).

Effective Date: September 13, 2018

Advertisement

Advertisement
